So I'm just going to discuss for a moment the nature of sort of random collaging as opposed to thinking about all of these very complex dynamics of highlights and shadows.
Because there's a lot of thinking that gets involved in making that process happen.
Whereas something like this piece which I did within, I don't know, maybe a half an hours time.
I wasn't really thinking about that.
I wanted to just be a little more random.
I cut the pieces at random.
I fit them at random a little more.
Similarly as I did in a piece such as this.
I wasn't really trying to consider shadow and highlights specifically.
Some areas I made sure were darker than others.
Some areas lighter than others to create dynamic.
But because this was more of an abstract piece, because this was more of a just purely collaged random piece it wasn't necessary for me to think oh I need to have a highlight here and a shadow there.
I was being a little more at random.
A little more free to cut pieces out, place them as I will and see how they worked together that way.